So I've started Datalab,
Eu iniciei o Datalab,
and I've opened up the featureengineering.ipythonnotebook,
abri o featureengineering.ipythonnotebook
and so let's now walk through this.
e vou mostrar como funciona.
So, in this notebook,
Neste bloco de notas,
we're going to learn how to work with feature columns,
veremos como trabalhar com colunas de atributos
we'll add feature crosses in TensorFlow.
e adicionar cruzamentos de atributos no TensorFlow.
We're going to be reading our data from BigQuery,
Vamos ler nossos dados no BigQuery,
creating data sets using Dataflow,
criar conjuntos de dados com o Dataflow
and we'll be using a wide and deep model.
e usar um modelo amplo e profundo.
So, we're going to put together a lot of these things that we talked about,
Vamos usar muito do que falamos até aqui.
the wide and deep we haven't quite talked about but we will talk about it now.
Só não falamos ainda sobre o modelo amplo e profundo.
So, here's the issue here.
Este é o problema.
So far, we've built a taxi cab model,
Até agora, criamos um modelo de táxi,
but we have not brought in human insight into it at all.
mas não incluímos insights humanos.
So, that's what we're going to do now,
É isso que faremos agora.
we're going to basically take some advantage of some
Aproveitaremos algumas das coisas
of the things that we know about how taxis work,
que sabemos sobre o funcionamento de um táxi,
about how New York is laid out,
sobre o mapa de Nova York,
and start giving the model hints,
e começaremos a dar dicas para o modelo
so that it can learn those things better.
para que ele possa aprender isso melhor.
So, as we walk through,
Conforme trabalhamos,
I'll talk about where a particular insight comes from.
falarei de onde vem um insight específico.
So, first thing is let's go ahead and get the import.
Primeiro, vamos…
Make sure to change your project.
Altere seu projeto.
So, I've changed my project to map to my Qwiklabs project,
Eu mudei meu projeto para mapear o projeto do Qwiklabs,
I've changed my bucket to map to my Qwiklabs bucket
mudei meu intervalo para mapear o intervalo do Qwiklabs
and I've set my region to map to where I want the code to run.
e mudei minha região para mapear onde o código será executado.
So, then, let's go ahead and run the query.
Vamos executar a consulta.
So, the query now actually does some cleanup.
A consulta faz uma limpeza.
So, here, I'm basically making sure
Basicamente, preciso garantir
that we're pulling in only data that has positive distances,
que só dados com distâncias positivas sejam extraídos,
that the fare amount is greater than 2.5,
para que "fare_amount" seja maior que 2,5,
that the pickup longitude,
para que "pickup_longitude",
pickup latitude, et cetera,
"pickup_latitude" etc.,
are within reasonable counts,
fiquem dentro de um limite razoável
and there were people in the taxi.
e que haja alguém no táxi.
So, we want to make sure that the data that was collected for
Precisamos garantir que os dados coletados
a particular taxi cab trip was correct before we actually use it for training.
em uma corrida específica estejam corretos antes de usá-los no treinamento.
I'm going to divide up my data as we talked about earlier,
Dividirei os dados, conforme mencionamos
when we talked about creating data sets based on the hash of the pickup date time.
quando falamos sobre como criar conjuntos de dados com base no hash do horário.
Having done that, I've created my query,
Depois, criei minha consulta,
and my query is basically going to take the toll amount, and the fare amount,
que vai coletar o valor e a tarifa,
and calling that the fare amount,
e chamarei de "fare_amount",
so that we're learning the total costs that will cost somebody,
para sabermos o custo total para uma pessoa,
and taking the day of the week as a day of the week.
e usando o dia da semana como "dayoftheweek".
Why do we take that? Well, we know that
Por que precisamos disso? Sabemos que
traffic conditions are going to be different depending on the day of the week.
as condições de trânsito são diferentes dependendo do dia.
We know that Fridays are going to have more traffic than Sundays.
Sabemos que a sexta tem mais trânsito que o domingo.
We also know that the hour of the day matters, even on Friday,
Também sabemos que a hora é importante, mesmo na sexta.
2:00 AM on a Friday is probably not going to have as much traffic as 4:00 PM on a Friday,
2h de sexta provavelmente não terá tanto trânsito quanto às 16h.
and why does this matter?
Por que isso é importante?
It matters because in New York,
Porque, em Nova York,
and this is something that human insight brings in,
e isso é algo que o insight humano oferece,
people pay for the amount of time they spent in a taxi in addition to the distance.
as pessoas pagam pelo tempo gasto, além da distância.
So, if the tax is stuck in traffic,
Se o táxi ficar preso no trânsito,
you're going to have to pay for it because you're occupying the taxi,
você paga por isso, porque está ocupando o táxi
and the taxi driver is not able to pick up other fares.
e o taxista não consegue pegar outras corridas.
So, the time matters,
O tempo é importante,
your time that's spent in the trip matters.
o tempo gasto na corrida é importante.
Before the trip starts,
Antes da corrida começar,
we don't know how long it's going to take.
não sabemos quanto tempo ela levará.
We want the machine learning model to have to learn this,
Queremos que o modelo de aprendizado de máquina aprenda isso,
and we know that a key determinant of how long
e sabemos que um fator determinante da duração
the trip takes is when the pickup happened.
da corrida é quando ela começou.
Not the drop-off, because we don't know where they're going to get dropped off,
Não o fim da corrida, porque não sabemos quando a pessoa sairá do táxi,
but we do know when they're going to get picked up.
mas sabemos quando ela começará a corrida.
So, we're basically using the pickup date time,
Basicamente, usamos o horário de início,
the day of the week, and the hour of the day as inputs to our model.
o dia da semana e a hora do dia como entradas para o modelo.
We also know where they're going to be picked up.
Também sabemos onde a corrida começará.
We also know where the customer wants to get dropped off.
E onde o cliente quer ser deixado.
We don't know the time they're going to get dropped off,
Não sabemos o horário de término da corrida,
but we do know where they're going to go.
mas sabemos para onde o cliente vai.
So, we know that drop-off longitude and the drop of latitude.
Conhecemos a longitude e a latitude do local.
So those are going to be our inputs as well.
Elas também farão parte da entrada.
We're going to take a passenger count,
Criaremos uma contagem de passageiros
and we're going to basically create a key.
e criaremos uma chave.
I'm going to use this key,
Eu usarei essa chave,
but if we wanted to do some kind of thing like batch prediction,
mas, se você quiser fazer um tipo de previsão em lote,
for example, we're going to be sending a lot of data in,
com a inserção de muitos dados,
it's helpful if each of the rows in your data set has a unique ID,
é útil se cada linha do conjunto de dados tiver um código exclusivo.
and so this is a unique ID form from all of the input columns.
Esse é um tipo de formulário de código das colunas de entrada.
So, at this point,
Neste momento,
we're now ready to create our data set.
estamos prontos para criar o conjunto de dados.
To create a data set,
Para criar o conjunto de dados,
we'll basically go ahead and remove any data set that may exist.
vamos excluir qualquer conjunto de dados existente.
Having done that, we will go ahead
Depois disso, podemos avançar
and create a CSV file from all of these columns.
e criar um arquivo CSV com essas colunas.
First thing is that we want to make sure that the columns are fare amount,
Primeiro, precisamos garantir que as colunas sejam "fare_amount",
day of the week, hour of the day, et cetera.
"dayoftheweek", "houroftheday" etc.
So, those are the columns that we want to do,
Essas são as colunas que queremos criar,
but the day of the week in the data set when we do BigQuery,
mas o dia da semana, no conjunto de dados do BigQuery,
the day of the week is going to be a number like 2.
será um número como 2.
We don't want a number like 2 because we don't know if 2,
Não queremos um número 2 porque não sabemos
what day of the week is it?
qual dia da semana ele é.
Does a week start with Sunday,
A semana começa no domingo,
or Monday, or Tuesday?
na segunda ou na terça?
We don't want to have our client code,
Não queremos que o código do cliente
et cetera, have to worry about that.
precise lidar com isso.
So, what we will do, is that we'll replace
O que fazemos é substituir
those magic numbers by the actual names of the days of the week.
esses números pelo nome dos dias da semana.
So, if the day of the week is one, it is Sunday.
Se o primeiro dia é o domingo,
If the day of the week is two,
e o número mostrado é 2,
it's Monday, et cetera.
significa segunda-feira.
So, that's exactly what I'm doing here.
É isso que estou fazendo.
I'm taking the BigQuery result,
Estou usando o resultado do BigQuery,
day of the week which is a number,
um dia da semana expresso como número,
and replacing it with a string,
e substituindo por uma string.
and now I'm basically appending them all with a comma in between,
Agora, eu reúno todos separados por vírgulas,
and that is now my CSV file output.
gerando um arquivo CSV.
Now, to write this out,
Agora, para gravar isso,
what I'm going to do is I'm going to read the data
eu preciso ler os dados
from BigQuery using this query that we just created,
no BigQuery usando a consulta criada
converting it to CSV using that function that I just talked about.
e convertê-la em CSV com a função que comentamos.
The only change that we are doing is that we are changing
A única alteração é que estamos mudando
the days of the week from magic numbers to strings.
os dias da semana de números para strings
Then writing it out to a text file, a CSV file.
e criando um arquivo de texto CSV.
Now, when I run this,
Agora, quando executo o código,
at this point, we basically have the code pre-process.
temos o pré-processamento do texto.
Right. In the next cell,
Na próxima célula,
I am calling the pre-process on the dataflow runner if I wanted,
posso chamar o pré-processamento no executor do Dataflow, se quiser,
or I could create a smaller dataset on the direct runner to run it locally.
ou posso criar um conjunto de dados menor para executá-lo localmente.
So, in this case, I will run it on the dataflow runner,
Nesse caso, eu executo no Dataflow,
and this is going to run,
ele será executado
and it's going to take a while.
e levará um tempo.
So, we'll go to the console,
Vamos para o console,
and we will see in dataflow runner that the job has started.
e podemos ver que o job foi iniciado no executor.
So, we'll go into dataflow and what does it happen? What is it saying?
Quando vamos para o Dataflow…
Dataflow. I see.
Dataflow…
It's a dataflow API has not been used or enabled,
Uma mensagem de que a API Dataflow não foi usada ou ativada.
so what we will have to do is that we will have to go in here.
Temos que vir aqui.
If you see that error,
Se você vir esse erro,
you will have to go into the APIs and
precisará acessar "APIs and Services"
So, the one that we want to enable is called data flow.
Queremos ativar o Dataflow.
So, when we do that, we get the dataflow API,
Quando procuramos, acessamos a API Dataflow.
and let's go ahead and enable the API.
Vamos ativar a API.
Once the API has been enabled,
Quando ela for ativada…
We should be able to rerun this cell.
Poderemos executar a célula novamente.
Okay. It has been enabled.
Certo, ela foi ativada.
So, now we go back to our Datalab Notebook and rerun this cell,
Agora, voltamos ao bloco de notas do Datalab e executamos a célula.
Okay. There it is. It has launched,
Pronto, deu certo.
and so I can now go back to the dataflow part of the menu,
Agora, posso voltar para o Dataflow no menu
and you will see that this code is running.
e você verá o código em execução.
This will take a while to run,
Isso demorará um pouco.
and when it's finished running,
Quando terminar,
on the cloud in your bucket,
na nuvem, no seu intervalo,
you will have training files that you can use for training.
você terá os arquivos que pode usar para o treinamento.
So, let's go ahead and wait for it to be done,
Vamos esperar ele terminar.
and then once it's done,
Quando terminar,
we would be able to come back.
poderemos voltar.
So, I'll pause the video here.
Vou pausar o vídeo aqui,
We'll come back and we'll start once the dataflow job is complete.
voltamos depois e continuamos quando o job for concluído.
We can see that this job took about eight minutes for me,
O job levou cerca de oito minutos,
the last step succeeded,
a última etapa foi bem-sucedida.
and at this point,
Nesse momento,
the number of workers is coming back down.
o número de workers está diminuindo novamente.
Of course, your mileage will vary depending on how many workers you have
A milhagem varia dependendo de quantos workers você tem
available and how many workers you actually have running in your job.
e quantos estão em execução no job.
But once it's done,
Quando terminar,
you can go back to the notebook and make sure that the output files exist,
você pode voltar ao bloco de notas e ver se os arquivos de saída estão lá.
and that's what I'm doing here,
É isso que estou fazendo.
I'm doing GS, on gsutil ls,
Estou usando GS no gsutil ls
on the bucket, and we see that there is a train.csv,
no intervalo, e consigo ver um arquivo train.csv
and there is a valid.csv.
e um arquivo valid.csv.
So, it basically have a training file under validation file,
Temos um arquivo de treinamento no arquivo de validação,
and we can also just go ahead and cut.
e também podemos usar "cut".
Cut is a Unix command that basically lists the first few.
"Cut" é um comando do Unix que lista as primeiras linhas.
Actually, it lists all of the lines and basically piping it through ahead,
Na verdade, ele lista todas e gera um canal
so that I get the first few lines,
para mostrar as primeiras linhas.
and we see that as we expect,
Assim, podemos ver o que esperamos,
the day of the week is a string: Friday, Wednesday, et cetera.
o dia da semana é uma string: sexta, quarta etc.
Then we basically have latitudes,
Nós temos latitudes,
longitudes, pickup, and dropoff points.
longitudes, pontos de início e término da corrida.
We also have the last thing.
Também temos uma última coisa.
The last column is a key that we will just ignore in our model,
A última coluna é uma chave que vamos ignorar no modelo,
but it's there if we want a unique ID for every row in our data set.
mas que existe se precisarmos de um código exclusivo para cada linha.
So, we have this file,
Este arquivo está pronto,
and now we can basically use it to develop our model.
e podemos usá-lo para desenvolver nosso modelo.
So, in order to do our development,
Para esse desenvolvimento,
it's good not to have to go back to the Cloud each time.
é melhor não precisar voltar sempre para o Cloud.
So, what I am doing is that I'm making a directory called
Por isso, farei um diretório chamado "sample"
Because we have shorted files,
Como temos arquivos fragmentados,
I'm just copying the first part of the shorted file into my local directory sample.
estou copiando apenas a primeira parte para a amostra do meu diretório local.
Having done this, we can now basically go ahead and look at our code itself.
Depois, podemos ver o código.
So, let's go ahead and look at our code.
Vamos ver nosso código.
We could do this in the notebook,
Podemos fazer isso no bloco de notas,
but let's go and look at it outside.
mas vamos ver fora dele.
So, we have our taxi fare.
Temos nossa tarifa de táxi.
So, in our taxi fare as before,
Nessa tarifa, assim como antes,
we will have a trainer,
temos um trainer e,
and as before, we will have a model.pi and tasks.pi.
como antes, temos model.pi e tasks.pi.
But model.pi, in this case,
Mas model.pi, nesse caso,
is not going to be just a raw input.
não será apenas uma entrada bruta.
It's going to have some feature engineering in it.
Ele terá alguma engenharia de atributos.
So, these are the columns that for present and notice
Estas são as colunas presentes, e observe
that we now have some extra columns from the ones that we had before.
que agora há algumas colunas a mais.
We have the day of the week,
Temos o dia da semana,
we have the hour of the day, et cetera.
o horário do dia etc.
So, what we're doing is that we're basically saying that these are my input columns,
Estas são as colunas de entrada,
I have the day of the week,
eu tenho o dia da semana,
it has a vocabulary which is a Sunday,
um vocabulário, constituído de domingo,
Monday, Tuesday, et cetera, the days of the week.
segunda, terça etc., os dias da semana.
The hour of the day is also a categorical column,
O horário também é uma coluna categórica,
but it has an identity.
mas tem uma identidade.
In other words, it already is an integerized number.
Ou seja, já é um número inteiro.
So, one, two, three, four, et cetera.
1, 2, 3, 4 etc.
Then, we have numeric columns for pickup longitude,
Depois, temos as colunas numéricas de longitude
pickup latitude, drop-off latitude,
e latitude de início, latitude
drop-off longitude, et cetera,
e longitude de término etc.
and then I'm also going to create
Eu também criarei
some engineered columns and we look at that later in the code,
algumas colunas com engenharia para usar posteriormente no código,
but the engineer columns are going to be the difference in latitude.
mas as colunas serão a diferença de latitude.
Now, why does that matter?
Por que isso é importante?
The difference in latitude basically tells you if you're going North-South in Manhattan.
A diferença de latitude diz se você vai do norte para o sul de Manhattan.
So, that's a pretty good idea of to how much change in latitude that's happened.
Isso dá uma ideia de quanto a latitude mudou.
The longitude difference is actually very useful
A diferença de longitude é útil,
because New York City is not south in extent,
porque Nova York não tem tanta extensão ao sul,
and all of the bridges on which you pay tolls tend to be dramatic changes in longitude.
e todas as pontes com pedágio geram mudanças drásticas na longitude.
So, knowing the longitude difference is also useful,
Por isso, é útil saber a diferença na longitude.
and I add in a Euclidean distance which is known as the bird flies,
Também adicionei uma distância euclidiana
between the pickup point and the dropoff point.
entre os pontos de início e de término.
That's a pretty good feature to use as well
Esse também é um bom recurso,
because that way the model doesn't have to learn distances,
porque o modelo não precisa aprender distâncias,
the distance is already given to it on a platter.
ela já é dada de início.
So, we basically do these feature engineering,
Nós fazemos essa engenharia de atributos
and now we're ready to build our estimator.
e estamos prontos para criar um Estimator.
In our estimator, we basically take all of our input columns.
No Estimator, nós usamos todas as colunas de entrada.
So, those are the input columns that we have,
Essas são as colunas que nós temos.
and then just as we did in our feature engineering exercise on the housing dataset,
Assim como no exercício de engenharia no conjunto de dados de armazenamento,
we bucketize the latitude buckets and the longitude buckets.
nós intervalamos a latitude e a longitude.
So, we take the pick up latitude and we bucketize them to between 38 and 42,
Nós intervalamos a latitude de início entre 38 e 42,
and the longitude from -76- -72 because this is New York,
e a longitude de -76 a -72, porque é Nova York
and those are the bounds of New York City.
e esses são os limites da cidade.
So, we go ahead and we get a bucketized pickup latitude,
Vamos intervalar a latitude de início,
a bucketized dropoff latitude,
a latitude de término
and the same thing for the longitudes.
e as longitudes,
Pickup longitude and dropoff longitudes,
tanto de início quanto de término.
all of them are bucketized.
Todas são intervaladas.
Once you have them bucketized,
Depois de intervalar,
what does bucketization do?
o que isso faz?
It discretizes things, it basically takes a numeric value,
Isso distingue as coisas, pega um valor numérico
and makes it categorical because it's in one of those buckets.
e o torna categórico, porque faz parte de um intervalo.
We take those categorical values,
Nós usamos esses valores categóricos
and we feature cross them.
e fazemos o cruzamento de atributos.
So, what happens when we feature cross the pickup latitude and the pickup longitude?
O que acontece quando cruzamos a latitude e a longitude de início?
So, we have the latitude and we have the longitude,
Nós temos a latitude e a longitude
and we feature cross it,
e fazemos o cruzamento de atributos.
we essentially put the pickup location,
Nós essencialmente colocamos
that's what ploc is.
Isso é o ploc.
Ploc is now like a grid cell.
Ploc agora é como uma grade.
Similarly, dloc is a grid cell that corresponds to the dropoff,
Do mesmo modo, dloc é uma grade que corresponde ao término.
these are both just grid-cells points.
Ambos são pontos em uma grade.
Now, I basically feature cross the pickup location and the dropoff location.
Eu faço o cruzamento de atributos dos locais de início e término.
So, now we're basically saying that let's learn from
Estamos falando para o modelo aprender
all the taxi trips from this location to this location, what do they cost?
com todas as corridas de táxi daqui até aqui. Quanto elas custam?
The only way that we can do this,
A única maneira de fazer isso,
and this is something that we have to repeat over and over
e isso é algo que precisamos repetir sempre,
again is that feature crossing is extremely powerful,
é que o cruzamento de atributos é muito poderoso,
but this only works if you have enough data because feature crossing is memorization.
mas só funciona se você tiver dados o bastante, porque ele usa memorização.
It's memorization, and it works if you have enough data in each of those buckets.
Ele funciona com memorização se você tiver dados suficientes nos intervalos.
In this case, we have millions of taxicab rides,
Neste caso, temos milhões de corridas de táxi,
so we have enough data and we can afford to do this.
então temos dados suficientes para fazer isso.
bucketize the dropoff longitude,
a longitude de término,
use it to create the pickup loc,
usamos para criar o ploc,
dropoff loc, do the feature cross of those,
o dloc, fazemos o cruzamento de atributos,
and now we have the a pick-up dropoff pair,
e agora temos um par de início e término
that's a feature cross as well,
que também é um cruzamento.
and then we do the day and hour, again,
Depois, usamos o dia e a hora,
because traffic depends on the day and the hour,
porque o tráfego depende dessas informações.
Friday 03:00 PM is different from Wednesday 03:00 PM is different from Sunday 3:00 pm.
Sexta às 15h é diferente de quarta às 15h e de domingo às 15h.
So, we do that cross and we have to decide on the number of buckets that we want to use.
Fazemos o cruzamento e decidimos o número de intervalos a ser usado.
of possible values to the fourth root of the possible number of values.
de valores possíveis até a quarta raiz do número possível.
In this case, I'm basically using the total number of values themselves.
Neste caso, estou usando o número total de valores.
24 by 7 for the number of buckets,
24/7 para o número de intervalos.
but that is something that you will have to try
Mas isso é algo que você precisa testar,
out and you will have to do hyper-parameter tuning on.
além de ajustar os hiperparâmetros.
There is no right answer here for how many hash buckets you should be using.
Não há uma resposta certa para quantos intervalos de hash usar.
Then we'll go back and look at all of our data,
Voltamos a analisar nossos dados
and say which of these are sparse
para dizer quais são esparsos
and categorical and which of these are dense and numeric?
e categóricos e quais são densos e numéricos.
The sparse and categorical columns go into
As colunas esparsas e categóricas ficam
the wide part of a network because linear models tend to work well for those,
na parte maior de uma rede, porque modelos lineares são melhores para elas.
and the dense and numeric columns
E as colunas densas e numéricas -
and embedding columns are an example of
colunas de incorporação são um exemplo
dense columns because we've taken the sparse data,
de colunas densas porque colocamos os dados esparsos
and put them into the shoe handed in,
em um espaço pequeno -
those are also useful things that are dense.
são úteis também.
So, we take all of our sparse columns and we throw them into the white columns,
Precisamos colocas nossas colunas esparsas nas colunas brancas.
we take all of our dense data,
Nossos dados densos
and we throw them into our deep columns,
vão para as colunas profundas,
and we create what is called a DNN linear combined regressor.
e criamos um DNNLinearCombinedRegressor.
So, this is an extra umph that we're giving to the model, if you wanted,
Isso é um recurso extra para o modelo. Se você quiser,
you could have just done a DNN regressor,
pode fazer apenas um regressor DNN,
parsing in all of these things as deep columns,
analisando tudo isso como colunas profundas.
and that would have been fine, but DNN linear combined lets us
Isso seria ótimo, mas o DNNLinearCombined permite
treat the sparse data differently from the dense data,
tratar os dados esparsos e os densos de maneiras diferentes.
uses a different optimizer for the sparse versus the dense,
Ele usa um otimizador diferente para os dados esparsos,
it is tuned to this idea that if you have a real-world dataset,
é ajustado para a ideia de que, em um conjunto de dados real,
some of your features will be dense and some of your features will be sparse,
alguns dos atributos serão densos e outros serão esparsos.
so this is a kind regressor that works very well for that kind of data.
Então, esse tipo de regressor funciona bem com esse tipo de dados.
So we're doing this, we're parsing in which of our features need a linear model,
Com isso, estamos analisando quais atributos precisam de um modelo linear
and which of our features need a deep neural net model,
e quais precisam de um modelo de rede neural profundo.
and we specify the number of units that we want for our DNN model.
Além disso, especificamos o número de unidades que queremos no modelo.
So that's our model,
Este é o modelo.
but remember that we talked about feature engineering.
Lembra que falamos sobre a engenharia de atributos?
We don't want to just take our raw data,
Não queremos apenas os dados brutos,
we want to add things to it,
queremos adicionar itens a eles,
and we had our feature engineering columns already,
e já temos colunas de engenharia de atributos:
the latdiff, londiff, well,
latdiff, londiff…
this is how you compute them.
é assim que você as processa.
The latdiff is essentially the difference of the two latitudes,
A latdiff é a diferença entre as duas latitudes,
the londiff is the difference of the two longitudes,
a londiff é a diferença entre as duas longitudes,
and then we specify the serving input function,
e depois especificamos a função de entrada de disponibilização,
this is what things does the end user have to give us.
ela diz o que o usuário final precisa fornecer.
The end-user does not have to give us a londiff and a latdiff,
O usuário não precisa fornecer latdiff e londiff,
they don't know how to compute it,
ele não sabe como computar,
they only have to give us a raw data.
só precisa fornecer os dados brutos.
So, we basically go through all of the input columns,
Nós passamos por todas as colunas de entrada,
except for the first two
exceto as duas primeiras,
which happened to be I think the free and fair amount which is a label,
que são o valor da tarifa, que é um marcador,
which is obviously not an input,
obviamente não é uma entrada,
and what is the second one that we are ignoring.
e a segunda estamos ignorando.
We go into our input columns,
Vamos ver as colunas de entrada.
the second one that we are ignoring,
A segunda que estamos ignorando…
We're ignoring the day of the week and we're ignoring the hour of the day.
Dia da semana e horário.
Everything else, we're basically taking it,
Usamos basicamente todo o resto
and basically saying that there's all floating point numbers,
para dizer que são números pontuais.
the day of the week is a string,
O dia da semana é uma string,
the hour of the day is an int 32,
e o horário é um int32.
and we basically use it to create a serving input receiver,
Ele basicamente é usado para criar um receptor de entrada,
but make sure that in addition to the features that the end users give us,
mas, além dos atributos fornecidos pelos usuários,
we add all of our engineered feature so that our model sees everything.
adicionamos os atributos com engenharia para que o modelo veja tudo.
So, at this point then no reading the data is very similar to what we have seen before,
Agora, a leitura dos dados é semelhante ao que já vimos,
the train and evaluate is very similar to what we have seen before,
o treinamento e a avaliação também,
and we can basically go ahead and run this.
então, podemos executar.
So let's go back here,
Vamos voltar aqui
and we can try out our model on a smaller dataset,
e testar nosso modelo em um conjunto de dados menor.
and then we can train it on the cloud.
Podemos treiná-lo na nuvem também.
So, we can basically go ahead and do GCloud ML Engine and when you run it,
Vamos para o GCloud ML Engine e, ao executar,
you should get a slightly better RMSE,
você gera um RMSE um pouco melhor,
but this by itself we've gotten a better model.
mas aqui temos um modelo melhor.
The next thing to do is basically do
O próximo passo é ajustar
hyper-parameter tuning to find good parameters of the model.
os hiperparâmetros para encontrar parâmetros bons do modelo.
In order to do that,
Para isso,
you would basically go ahead and we'll talk about hyper-parameter tuning,
falaremos sobre o ajuste de hiperparâmetros,
where you basically getting the parameters for those models,
em que você recebe os parâmetros para esses modelos.
in this case these turned out to be the best parameters.
Neste caso, estes foram os melhores.
So, having done that,
Depois de fazer isso,
we can now run this on a much larger dataset.
podemos executar em um conjunto de dados muito maior.
One of the key things about machine learning is that you get
Um aspecto importante do aprendizado de máquina
the best performance by training on large datasets.
é que você consegue o melhor desempenho com conjuntos grandes.
So, where earlier I did a dataflow job that would finish in about 10 minutes or so,
Antes, eu executei um job do Dataflow que levaria 10 minutos
so that we could get going.
para continuarmos.
We're now going to do a dataflow job that
Agora, vamos executar um job do Dataflow
runs for about an hour that creates a much larger,
que dura cerca de uma hora para criar um conjunto
a million row dataset,
muito maior, com milhões de linhas.
and then we can train on it,
Podemos treinar nele.
and having done that,
Depois disso,
you will basically see a much better RMSE.
você verá um RMSE muito melhor.
But the key idea here is to basically take your raw data and do
Mas a ideia principal é usar seus dados brutos
into the kinds of things that matter, traffic,
nos elementos importantes, como tráfego,
the distance of the trips,
distância das corridas,
whether they cross the boundaries,
se elas cruzam limites,
whether they go East-West or North-South etc, the londiff,
o sentido delas nas distâncias londiff,
the latdiff, the Euclidean distance,
latdiff e distância euclidiana,
the feature crosses, all of these are going to help improve our model.
o cruzamento de atributos, tudo isso melhora seu modelo.